PHAN NGUYEN

829 Beacon Street, Boston, MA 02215 | phananh.nguyen.vn@gmail.com | 781-472-0863 linkedin.com/in/phan-anh-nguyen | pab-nguyen.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Business analyst with prior experience in Oracle NetSuite, Tableau visualizations, data analytics, VBA scripting, and financial modeling. Strong analytical and collaboration skills gained by working with clients in financial services and pharmaceutical industries. Specifically trained in Python (NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn), Excel VBA, R (ggplot2), SQL, and Tableau. Working on an MS degree in Analytics and Google Data Analytics certificate.

EXPERIENCE

DEKKO Group JSC Oracle NetSuite Analyst

Hanoi, Vietnam

- Jan 2021 Present
- Extracted operational and financial data from Oracle NetSuite (SuiteAnalytics); cleaned, transformed and built dashboards with Tableau; analyzed and presented insights to executives.
- Performed as remote help desk, assessed system issues, communicated with end-users regarding operational problems, provided weekly training sessions to ensure smooth transition from legacy platform.
- Customized front-end elements (forms, lists, workflows), updated records, and documented changes and instructions.

Sunovion Pharmaceuticals

Marlborough, MA

Intern, Strategic Pricing and Contracting

Jun 2020 - Oct 2020

- Streamlined operational activities with VBA Macros scripting, improved efficiency and productivity to department.
- Reduced time spent on processes: Part D rebate from 10 hours to 30 minutes, Market Access customer report from two hours to 10 minutes, Medicaid invoices reconciliation from five hours to an hour.
- Built financial models to quantify monetary impacts of potential changes in health insurance policies, presented findings to Health Policy & Reimbursement team, notified management of \$300 million in potential liability.
- Led team of six colleagues to brainstorm, develop and pitch a best-in-class intern program recommendation to HR.

IPA Asset Management

Hanoi, Vietnam

Intern, Investment Analyst

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Constructed valuation models using DCF, Multiples, and NAV method with Excel, evaluated stocks in oil and plastics industries, issued recommendations for portfolio managers.
- Pitched seven stocks in plastics industries to aid portfolio managers in making accurate and timely investment decisions regarding firm's \$3M+ portfolio.
- Examined shareholders' meetings, conference calls, and analyst meetings transcripts of 10+ firms in construction and plastics industry to garner information on stock price moves.

EDUCATION

University of North America

Fairfax, VA

Master of Science; Management and Data Analytics

Aug 2022

Bentley University McCallum Graduate School of Business

Waltham, MA

Master of Science: Finance

Aug 2020

Bentley University

Waltham, MA

Bachelor of Science; Corporate Finance and Mathematical Sciences, Cum Laude

May 2019

ACADEMIC & PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Vietnamese College Entrance Exam Analysis (2021): scraped 74,000 exam takers data from official Exam Results website using Python; cleaned, transformed data, and visualized insights using Tableau Public.
- Exploratory Analysis of Goodreads Data (2020): analyzed and visualized personal reading data from 2018 to 2020 extracted from Goodreads using R Studio (ggplot2).
- France Boissons Database Design (2019): designed and developed operational database infrastructure and business queries for France Boissons leveraging Oracle SQL Developer with a group of six members.